[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] So now we know how to
output data.
In modern web applications,
that's only half of what you do though.
You also need to react to user input.
You need to react to events.
You wanna make dynamic pages.
After all, this is one of the main reasons for using
a framework like Vue.
It makes building highly reactive and dynamic,
web applications easier.
Therefore, that's what we're going to focus on next,
and attached you'll find a simple starting project,
which is not too different from the one before.
We just have a slightly different content.
Still got a section with a different ID now,
and in there we've got two buttons, add and remove.
We also have a paragraph, where I output a counter,
which is managed in his Vue app,
which is created for you already.
It's a very simple Vue app here, as you can tell,
pretty empty, just has to state a method,
where I returned my data,
which only consists of a counter in the end,
which is a number, starting at zero.
And then mount this to the events section,
which is this section that holds all that markup.
Now at the moment, those buttons don't do anything.
If I press them, you'll see that well, nothing happens.
And that's exactly what we wanna work on.
I wanna show you how you can react to user input,
and how you now can really leverage Vue,
to make a more interactive and reactive web application.
Let's say, when this button, the add button,
when this button is pressed,
we wanna add one, to the counter.
And the remove button, or reduce maybe.
When the reduce button, is pressed,
we wanna deduct one from the counter.
Let's start with the add button, how could we do that?
In regular JavaScript,
we would get access to the button with document,
get element by ID.
If that button had an ID or with query selector,
and selecting the first button we find,
and we could add an EventListener,
with the addEventListener method.
That is how we would do it,
in the vanilla JavaScript, without Vue.
But we're using Vue,
so that we don't have to do it like this,
so that we don't have to, define step by step,
what should happen, but that we instead can leverage,
this declarative approach, and just declare,
our end result and let Vue figure out how to get there.
And therefore, thankfully,
Vue gives us an easier way of adding EventListeners,
to HTML elements.
If we wanna add a click listener to this button,
we can use a never Vue directive.
We learned about V-bind.
V-bind is helpful for setting the value of an attribute.
Now for adding EventListeners,
we have another directive, and that's the V-on directive,
because we wanna react on, a certain event.
V-on takes a so-called argument, after a colon,
just like V-bind, took the attribute,
which should be bound.
V-on takes the event to which you wanna listen,
after the colon.
In this case, click.
Now in case you're wondering to which events you can listen.
Well, all the default events you can listen to
on HTML elements.
So that would be click, mouseenter, mouseleave,
really anything you can listen to
in vanilla JavaScript as well.
Here, it's the click to which I wanna listen.
And then after an equal sign,
between the opening and closing double quotes,
we now specify the code that should run,
when the click occurs.
And that could be counter plus, plus,
which is the shortest form of writing and JavaScript,
that we wanna to add one, to the counter.
And that's just JavaScript code, nothing Vue specific.
As with V-bind at the double curly braces,
you can have simple JavaScript expressions,
right here in your HTML code,
in the parts that are managed by Vue.
Like here with V-on.
If I now save that in reload, I can click add,
and you will see that the counter, gets bigger,
every time I clicked this button, thanks to this code.
Now try doing, well, basically the same,
just with reducing the counter, on this button.
Were you successful.
Well, of course it shouldn't be too difficult,
it's essentially the same code.
We wanna react to a click event, with V-on click.
And then here, we just have counter minus, minus,
or the longer form would also work of course.
It's totally up to you, what you write there.
With that you can also reduce the counter.
So now we can add, and reduce.
And that's pretty, pretty nice.
And this is, how we can listen to user events in Vue.
And here's one super important thing,
which is easy to overlook,
which shows us why, we use Vue, and how powerful Vue is.
You might notice that we don't have much code here,
some HTML code, and definitely not a lot of JavaScript code.
I mean, this here is all the JavaScript code we wrote.
Yet, we have two EventListeners, and a counter that changes,
and most importantly, and easy to overlook,
we got a counter that's being output here,
where the page the users sees,
changes every time the counter changes.
This minus six here, changes to a minus five,
if I click the button,
and that's not something which would normally happen
in a webpage.
You would need to write JavaScript code,
that adds EventListeners, changes the counter.
And then when the counter changes,
reaches out to that paragraph,
to change the value that's showing up there.
And that's exactly what Vue does behind the scenes for you.
That is the core asset of frameworks like Vue.
You just declare, where you wanna have EventListeners,
and where you wanna output values,
and which values you should be aware of.
And Vue us all the rest of adding
and managing those listeners,
updating the counter behind the scenes.
And most importantly,
detecting when the counter changes,
and updating the parts of the real rendered page,
where updating is needed,
when that counter changes.
This is what Vue does behind the scenes.
This is a,
core feature of Vue.
This built in reactivity,
it detects that the counter changes,
when you click a button, and it's then finds the places,
on the page where the counter is used,
to update what the user sees,
with JavaScript behind the scenes.
I'm really emphasizing this
because it's so important to understand what Vue does here,
and hopefully why that's pretty amazing,
and makes our life, as a developer, much, much easier.
Well, and that's how we can get started with events in Vue.
Now let's see what else we can do with them.