Now we learned how to listen to events.
Now here's one important thing.
Currently, I'm updating the counter here in my HTML code.
In the Vue control parts, but in the HTML code
and it's generally is considered a bad
or not optimal practice to do that.
You don't wanna put too much logic into your HTML code.
Instead, the HTML code should really
just be about outputting stuff.
Logic like this, even though it's not too complex,
should typically go into your JavaScript code.
Now how could we get this logic into our JavaScript code?
Well, we wanna do something on every click.
What do you typically use
if you wanna do something at a certain point of time,
potentially in a repeated way?
Well, you need a function that can be called.
You need a function,
which you can call when the Add button is clicked
and you need a function which you can call
when the Reduce button is clicked.
Now of course, we could specify a function here, add,
and there, try to set counter equal to counter plus one.
But for multiple reasons,
this wouldn't work
for one counter is not a globally available variable,
it is a data property,
hence it's not available here.
In addition, even if it would be available
for whatever reason,
add now is a globally created function.
But in your Vue controlled HTML code,
you can't use such a function.
You can only use in this Vue controlled HTML part,
what is defined in your Vue app.
And that's why we use methods for that,
and we did already learn about methods before.
Now, we don't just use methods to manually call them
as we did before, we can also use methods to connect them,
to event listeners and let Vue call them for us
when a certain event occurs.
For example, here, we can add a add method,
though this name here is totally up to you,
you could also name it add counter or increment
or whatever you want, but I'll name it add.
And in here, you can now update this counter,
just important as you learned with this counter.
In your JavaScript code,
you refer to your data properties with this.
This counter plus plus,
or the longer form this counter
equals this counter plus one, it's the same.
And with that, we have a method which we can call
to update our counter.
Now this method doesn't return anything
because it doesn't have to.
We'll not use the method like we did before
to dynamically output something here.
Instead, we're using it to run it when a click occurs
and therefore, this does need to return anything
because the click listener doesn't want a return value.
So now here, we can call add like this
and if I now saved it and reload, I can click add
and it still works because we're executing the same code
just in a different way.
And this is actually the batter way of doing it,
putting your logic into JavaScript
and just pointing at that logic.
That is generally considered better,
even though technically, it here works in the same way.
But consider cases where you have more complex logic
and it quickly makes sense that you should put that logic
into JavaScript and not into HTML.
So it's not bad to get started with that as a habit,
right from the start.
Now besides calling add like this, by the way,
you can also just point at it
so that you tell Vue, "Hey, that's the name of the function
"or of the method to be precise.
"You should execute when a click occurs."
Vue accepts both, you explicitly calling it like this,
or you pointing at it,
Vue detects what you're doing,
and it will do the right thing in both cases.
Now typically, you just wanna point at it
since that is closer to vanilla JavaScript
and how you would set up an event listener there
but it is worth noting that both syntaxes are allowed
as you can see here.
Well, and now let's do the same for reducing our counter.
Of course, try this on your own.
Here's a quick pause for you to do that
and there after, we'll do it together.
Were you successful?
Well, again, it's pretty much the same code.
We can add a reduce method,
again, this name is up to you
and in there, we just set this counter
equal to this counter minus one, or we use the shorter form,
which looks like this, which is also okay.
And now in here on this second button,
we can call reduce like this, or as I just mentioned,
just point at it, both is accepted.
And now we've got our working buttons
with one important change,
now the logic is outsourced into JavaScript,
which is where your logic should be
and the HTML code is cleaner
and this is better.
This is considered to be better,
so it is a good idea to get started with this approach
and with this pattern.
Now that is how we can use methods.
We cannot just use them in curly braces or with the bind
to dynamically derive a value we wanna output
but we can also use them with event listeners
to define codes that should be executed
when the event occurs.
And in reality, you will more often use methods
to connect them to events,
than you will use them
to output something dynamically derived.
I just showed this before to show you that it's possible
and to introduce methods
but typically, you'll use them like this
in combination with event listeners.