Okay. So we learned quite a bit about events.
What if we now don't just want to add one and subtract one,
but we want to be able to add five and reduce this by five?
Maybe name it Subtract therefore, whatever you want.
But the goal is that we now don't just add and deduct one,
but instead five, how would we do that?
Well, we of course,
could accept a parameter in those methods, right?
That is how we would probably do it in JavaScript.
We can accept a parameter, number, or number, or n,
totally up to you,
it's your method so you can accept whatever you want.
And then we could add num here or reduce num.
Of course, we could also make this less dynamic
and just hard-code five here.
The problem just is that whenever we plan to
change this number, we need to change it down there in code.
So it typically would be better
to have a more dynamic method,
which gets the number which we wanna add or remove,
and then uses this as a parameter like this.
Then these methods will never need to be changed
when we decide to deduct or add a different number.
So that's the more generic and therefore,
typically better way of writing these methods.
But how do we tell Vue that it should call
add and reduce with a value of five
for these parameters?
Well, keep in mind,
we can execute add like this by pointing at it
or by calling it explicitly.
Well, and if we called it like this, we're as a developer,
in full control over the value we wanna pass
to the parameters of these methods.
So here we can add five for example,
and reduce by five, just like that.
And now whenever we decide to go for a new value,
we just have to change it here in HTML,
where we're changing the caption of the button anyways,
and the method will work correctly automatically
because it's written in a very generic way.
So if we now save that and reload,
I can add 10 and subtract five and it just works.
So passing arguments to methods is also possible,
and it's very easy to do,
and this is an important pattern to know.
This is important to understand, because in reality,
in apps you're building with Vue,
you will sometimes have the scenario
that your method needs to get some parameter,
which you as a developer want to set,
and as you see, setting it and telling Vue
to call this method with this value is super, super easy.