So this is taking shape.
Let's now enhanced his mini dummy app here a little bit.
And let's add an input of type text here, just like this.
And below that paragraph where I say Your Name
and in here, I wanna output the username.
But now the user should be able to enter the name
in this input here, that's the new thing.
So we can have a name field here in our data.
Initially it could be empty or your name, whatever you want.
And we can output the name here
with the double curly braces.
But now I also have this input here
and whenever I type in here, I want to update the name,
which is output in this paragraph.
Now, how could we do that?
Well, now that we learned about listening to events,
we should have all the tools we need for that.
We can add an event listener with v-on
and now of course, I don't wanna listen to the click event,
but to every keystroke.
We could do it as with keyup or keydown,
which all have their special behaviors.
The best event to listen to on an input HTML element
is the input event.
Which is a default Dom event
available on input elements, nothing Vue specific.
You can listen to the input event
in vanilla JavaScript as well.
Here with v-on I'm telling Vue that I want to listen
to this input event on this input element.
And there for now, again,
we can specify to code between these double quotes
that should execute when an input event is admitted,
which will be the case on every keystroke.
That is how the input event is emitted by default.
So now again, we could put the code in here
or use this better approach of using a method.
So I'll do that, add a little method here,
setName could be the method name,
because that's what we're going to do.
Again, the name is up to you,
but of course you wanna name the method
such that it describes what it's going to do.
So here I'll use setName
and then I want to set this name.
So this name property, which we added to our data object
equal to what the user entered.
And that's going to be a bit tricky, won't it?
Because how do we know what the user entered?
We know that the user entered something
because we're listening to that event,
but how do we get the concrete value the user entered?
While there is a built in behavior built into JavaScript,
not into Vue, which we can leverage.
First of all, we can point at the setName method here,
which is the method we wanna execute on every keystroke.
And now there's a cool behavior in JavaScript,
not in Vue, Vue just also is able to use it.
When you add an event listener
and you then point at a function that should be executed
when that event occurs.
That function will automatically get one argument.
The browser will ensure
that this argument is provided so to say.
And that will be an object
describing the event that occurred.
So here in setName,
we can accept this one argument, this one parameter.
You can name it however you want,
but you will always get this by the browser.
We would have gotten this here for add and reduce as well.
We just overrode it
with our own custom argument, we're passing in.
But since I'm not executing setName
with parentheses here, but I am pointing edit,
I don't override it.
And I let the browser provide this default event object.
And why is this useful?
Because this default event object
will be full of information about the event.
And for example, it will give us information
about the HTML element on which this event occurred,
which is the input element.
And we can then read the current value stored in this input
from that input element.
And we get access to the target off the event
with events.target and that's vanilla JavaScript.
This is nothing Vue specific.
This would work in vanilla JavaScript as well.
This gives us access to the element
on which the event occurred.
And this is the input element in this case,
which will have a value property.
Again, that's just vanilla javaScript
and you can search for MDN input
to find more documentation on this input element.
And in here you will eventually somewhere find
that this has a value property,
which you can use to read what the user entered.
So this will be the value to user entered,
setName will be called on every input events.
So on every keystroke and this should update the name,
our data and it property here with every keystroke,
with the value to user currently entered here.
And then we're outputting name down there.
And if we now save that in reload,
I can enter Maximilian and you see how this updates
in the paragraph below.
And that's Vue's reactivity in action, again.
It allows us to listen to this event and execute this code
and it's then all the detects that name changed
and updates it in the places on the page
where updating is needed.
And as a side note,
if I inspect this here in the Chrome Dev Tools,
there is something ever interesting which we can notice.
If you watch this part on the right here this HTML code.
You'll see that the parts
that are rerendered the browser flash,
you see the paragraph with my name flashes.
Now you will also see
that nothing else on the screen flashed.
For example, the counter didn't flash.
This counter only flashes. If I changed the counter.
Now these are the parts
which are actually rerendered on the screen.
And you see that only the parts that really changed in code
are rerendered on the screen and that's important.
If Vue would update the entire screen,
whenever something changed somewhere,
this would be bad for performance.
Instead Vue is really smart and it sees that
with every keystroke here, only the name changes.
And hence it only finds the places where I used the name,
in this case, this paragraph and update stat
and the rest is well left untouched.
And hence we save performance or have a better performance.
Now, this is how we can work with events.
There's just one more note about this default event object.
You could have a scenario that you need to call
your method explicitly on your own here
as we did it with add and reduce.
For example,
because you need to pass in some other argument,
like second name, which I always want to use here.
We could accept this here, second name or last name
and then update name with whatever the user entered
plus last name, maybe also add a white space in front of it.
The problem with that is that we now no longer
get this default event object as a first argument here.
Now to still pass that in, there is a special variable,
which you can use here in your template
and that's dollar sign event.
This is a reserved name and Vue gives this variable to you
to give you access to this built in default event object,
which you get automatically by the browser.
So that you can use it here in this code as well.
And for example, still pass it in as a first argument
to setName, if you wanted to.
So whenever you find yourself using an arguments here
or you simply can't just point at a function
for whatever reason and you need that built in event,
you can access it with dollar sign event.
But again, this is only needed if you're not just
pointing at the method as we did it before.
Hence now if a reload, this still all works as before,
but now with help of dollar sign event.
That's just in our side note,
because sometimes this is exactly what you need
to get access to both to build an event object
you get automatically and still execute code
on your own explicitly,
for example, to pass in your own arguments.