Now to conclude this introduction to events,
which is another core feature, as you can clearly tell,
let me show you one other directive
which you will very rarely need, but which sometimes
in niche scenarios could be helpful.
Let's say for whatever reason, here in this app,
we want to make sure that when we change the counter here,
the output here doesn't change, so that the initial value
of the counter is preserved here.
Now, you might wonder why we might want to do that.
Let's say we have a number of paragraph,
where we simply output the starting counter value.
And we wanna point at the counter property
we're managing in our Vue instance, so that,
if we ever change it here,
we do reflect that correct starting counter here.
But we want to make sure that
the starting counter never changes.
And right now of course, since we reference counter,
it will change whenever we change to counter.
If you have such a scenario that you have some data
that changes and you want to preserve the initial state
and not reflect any other changes,
there is a special directive you can put on to the element
where you are using that dynamic value in.
And that's the V once directive which is built into Vue.
This tells Vue that any dynamic data bindings,
like this interpolation here on this element,
should only be evaluated once.
So if data value changes thereafter, here in this place,
it will not be reflected it will not be updated.
So now if I reload, we see the starting counter 10 here,
but if I change the counter, it only changes down there
in the second green box and not in the first one.
Now again, this is a niche feature, but it is useful
to be aware of it if you ever had a scenario like this
where you need to lock an initial value in,
we once can help you with that.