So back in the project worked on before.
A bit simplified, I dumped the event modifiers,
I dumped v-ons and you find this snapshot attached
to this lecture in case you all don't want to start from,
well, this state again.
So I'm back in this project
where we have this input element that the buttons
for the counter and so on.
Now let's say our goal is to have another button
maybe here below the input where we say resetInput.
And the buttons should do what the name implies.
It should reset the input in, well, the input element.
For that, we can add a new method,
resetInput, or however you wanna name it.
And in there, how do we do that?
In there we now want to be clear this input.
Now we could try to get access to the input
through JavaScript with document.querySelector, for example,
get access to the input like this,
access to value property and set it to an empty string.
This might actually work, but it's very hacky.
We're not using Vue to then fall back
to such explicit JavaScript instructions.
That's not the idea behind using Vue.
Instead, we wanna stay in the Vue world
and leverage Vue and its features for that.
So how could we do that?
Well, we could use the name, data property,
which is the value we're ultimately updating
on every key stroke.
And output it here in input by setting value,
the value attribute equal to name, however, not like this,
but instead since name is dynamic and managed by Vue
with help of v-bind.
With that I'm making sure that name is reflected here.
So this name here is reflected in the input.
Why am I doing that?
Well if I now go to resetInput
and set this name equal to an empty string,
that empty value should be reflected in the input
and we should be able to set it back to an empty string.
Now we'll have one problem with that.
And that is that in set name,
I'm not setting name to just what the user enters,
but to what the user enters plus the last name.
And that would lead to a strange behavior
if we then reflect name back into this input here,
I can actually show it to you.
If I reload you'll see if I start typing
Schwartzmueller gets added over and over again,
which is not the idea.
So for the moment, let's get rid of this last name,
which we add here.
And let's just store what the user enters
with every keystroke in name,
and then reflect named back into the input
so that there we really reflect what the user entered.
And now let's also connect this button here with v-on:click
to this newly added resetInput method
so that this is triggered
when the resetInput button is pressed.
And with that, if I now reload,
I can enter Max here and it all works.
But if I click resetInput, we cleared it.
We also cleared in the paragraph
because there we're referring to the same name,
which we reset here,
but that's just a little side effect here.
Of course if you wanted to prevent that,
we could use a separate value, which would be output here,
which be confirmed upon hitting enter or anything like that.
I showed this before, how we could work with two values,
confirmed input and irregular input,
but that's not what this is about.
Instead, what this is about is about the fact that
this is a pattern you could need in some occasions.
You might have inputs where you don't just want
to get the value the user entered,
but where you also want to set the value
of the input so that you, for example,
can reset it with a button or any other logic
you have on your page.
And you can then achieve this
by not just listening to the input,
but by also sending the stored value back into the input
by binding the value property.
This is a common pattern you could need.
And actually it's so common
that you need something like this
that Vue has a shortcut for this you could say.
It has a special built in directive which simplifies this.
If you bind the value and listen to input changes on input,
you can get rid of all of that.
So both of the value binding and the input event listening,
get rid of both and instead add a new directive
on the input, the v-model directive.
And this v-model directive now simply wants
the data property it should manage for you,
so in our case, the name property.
The name property now is managed by Vue
such that it's updated on the input event
and the name properties value is then sent back
into the input element.
So v-model is simply just a shortcut for v-bind value
and v-on input,
v-model is just a shortcut for this.
And if I now save that and reload,
we therefore get the same behavior as before
but with less code.
And this is a concept called two-way binding
because we're communicating in both ways,
we are listening to an event coming
out of the input element you could say to the input event.
And at the same time, we're writing the value back
to the input element through its value attribute,
through its value property.
That's why it's called two-way binding
because we communicate in both directions.
And this is useful,
it makes getting user input and updating it
much easier as you can tell,
it's less code and therefore absolutely
a pattern and specifically a directive
you should keep in mind.