So now at this point,
we know a couple of things.
We learned about DOM interaction,
and that's a complex term with that I mean
that we learned how to make a part of the DOM,
the template of our Vue app by mounting the Vue app to it.
We learned about data binding,
with the bind and string interpolation, and also v-HTML,
and we learned about event handling with v-on,
but also with v-model.
To be precise, v-model is two-way binding,
and therefore the combination of data binding
and event handling so to say.
Now, it's time to dive into a third,
big block that makes up Vue.
This block has no official name,
but I like to call it advanced reactivity.
Vue is very reactive,
we already see that in a lot of places.
When I type here, the name here updates,
and Vue does that for us.
The same if we change the counter, so that all works.
But we have even more features
than what we know about thus far.
And I wanna start by coming back to methods
besides using them with events,
and then show you a better alternative to methods
for certain use cases.
Now, in this app here, we add it to a binding,
but to add it, we had to get rid of our last name here.
Now, that's not too bad
because the way we made the entered name,
a full name by adding a last name wasn't ideal anyways,
using this setName method, passing in this argument,
it worked but as you see, as soon as you want to do more,
for example, adding a reset functionality,
it's pretty hard to implement it like this,
that's why we had to get rid of it.
But that's no problem, we can output a full name here,
in a different way.
For example, we can add a new method,
anywhere where you want` by the way,
the order of methods here does not play a role.
So I will add it at the top.
And we'll name it, outputFullname,
because that's what this method should do.
It should return something, because I'm not going to use it
to bind it to an event,
but instead I'm going to use it to call it here,
in the curly braces,
I wanna call outputFullname, like this.
And therefore I wanna get back to full name here,
which then will be inserted in this part of the HTML code.
And therefore here I wanna return this name,
which is the entered name,
so this name property, which we're managing with v-model,
plus a blank space, plus Schwarzmuller,
and of course this Schwarzmuller could also be fetched
from another input, here it's simply hard-coded.
And if it's now saved and then reload,
we see Schwarzmuller here at the beginning,
and if I enter Maximilian,
we see Maximilian Schwarzmuller.
Now since I'm using a method we can even add an if check
and check if this name is currently empty,
and if it is empty we just return an empty string here,
so that we only add Schwarzmuller if the name is not empty.
So here we leveraged the fact
that we're having a method to return different values based
on different values and name.
And with that if I saved as a reload,
we make sure that we initially don't see anything,
and we only see full name with Schwarzmuller included
if I did enter a real name,
and as soon as that's empty again, the full name is gone.
So that's pretty nice,
however, it's not the best way of doing that.
"Now why is that not the best way of doing it?"
Well, if I type here we update the name
and output down there, that's good.
The problem is if I press this counter button,
we don't see a problem,
but behind the scenes Vue does something,
which is not ideal.
When we change the counter,
Vue basically tries to find out,
where on this page, it needs to update the rendered page.
So for example, if the counter changes Vue sees
that in this paragraph we're using to counter
and hence it needs to well update this part here
on the real page, that's exactly why we use Vue,
it updates the page for us automatically.
The problem is if we call a method like this here,
this method will also be re-executed by Vue,
whenever anything on the page changes,
because Vue can't know what this method does.
It doesn't know wherever,
maybe the counter gets used in there.
Well, if the counter changed,
and this method maybe uses the counter
this method should be re-executed, right?
Well, and for that reason Vue goes ahead,
and re-executes any method
you're using anywhere in your HTML code
between curly braces, or with the bind, or with the HTML,
so any non-event bound method will be re-executed by Vue,
whenever anything on the screen changes.
Even if like in this case, we know that in this method,
we're not using the counter.
We know it, but Vue doesn't.
And from a performance perspective, that's not so great.
And we can see this by the way,
we can add a console log here running again,
and if I now, increase this a little bit,
open up the browser developer tools,
and go to the JavaScript console part,
you will see that if I reload here,
we see running again initially,
but if I change to counter, we also see it running again,
being executed over and over again,
even though we just changed to counter.
Still outputFullname was executed again,
for the reasons I just specified.
And that's not a back, that's how Vue works.
And that's why methods are not the best solution
for outputting some dynamically calculated value like this,
but what is a better solution then?