Well, you could of course put your code in here.
Name plus Schwartz Muller, for example,
you could put it in here.
And if you do that, you avoid this problem.
Now view is able to see what's getting used here
and it will only updated this paragraph
and only reevaluated if well,
in this case name changed
and output full name has never called
and therefore will never be called by view.
But now we have more logic in our HTML code
and that's again, not good as you learned.
So there is a third nice feature we can use,
computed properties.
Computed properties are essentially like methods
with one important difference view will be aware
of their dependencies and only reexecute them
if one of the dependencies changed.
Computed is the third big configuration option
we learn about for the app we created.
The first one was data.
The second one was methods.
The third one is computed.
You can add it anywhere in this conflict object
here I will add it between data at methods,
but the position doesn't matter.
So you add computed here and just like methods and data.
This is not a name you can choose.
That is a name you have to use
because it's one of the key options,
supported by view in view apps.
Computed like methods wants an object.
So you pass an object as a value to compute it.
And now in computed,
you define a bunch of methods just like in methods,
but the methods you defined and computed will be called
and executed differently.
That's why we have these two different blocks.
So here we could add a full name method,
and I'm naming it full name and not output full name,
even though I could, because that name is up to you,
but I'm naming it like this because we're going to use this
like a data property, not like a method,
even though technically it is a method,
but we're not going to use it as such.
We're not going to call it.
And therefore you should name your computed properties
just as you would name your data properties.
And now in here,
we wanna return to value that eventually should be yielded
by that computed property
and there I'll just copy the exact same code
I had in my output full name method.
So I'll copy that code and put that in there.
And now, as I mentioned, we can use this full name,
computed property in our HTML code like this.
And that's important.
Not like this without parentheses,
you don't call it
you just point at it and view we'll call it for you.
We use it just like we use data properties
like to counter here.
And that's why we should also name our computed properties
like data properties,
because we use them like properties like variables.
We don't use them like functions.
So full name here will be connected
to this full name computed property
so the name of course has to be equal.
And now view will execute this for you.
It will basically check
if there is a full name data property.
And if there isn't, it will check
If there may be as a computed property with the name
and if that's the case, it will execute it.
And hence, if I saved us here in reload,
we see nothing here initially.
But as soon as I start typing,
we see the full name show up again.
So we've got the same behavior as before,
but now with one important difference,
let's check the developer tools again.
In there If I reload,
you will notice running again once initially of course,
because it needs to evaluate the value returned by full name
when the app is first rendered to discreet.
But now if I cleared it, if I changed my counter,
we don't see running again and keep in mind
that with a method, we did see it,
but now that's no longer the case.
We only see it if we type here,
which makes a lot of sense because here we really changed
something that's being used in that computed property.
We change the name with every keystroke.
So with computer properties,
view is aware of the dependencies
off the computer properties.
So in this case, that name is a dependency
and it will cache the computed property value
and only recalculate and reevaluate it
if one of the dependencies in this case,
the only dependency we have the name property changed.
And that's the key difference for performance.
It's better to use computer properties that methods
for outputting values In most cases.
only use methods if you know that you want to recalculate
a value whenever anything on the page changed.
In most scenarios, that will not be the case.
You only want to recalculate a value
if a dependency changed.
And that's when computed properties shine.
You still need methods either because you have something
that you really want to reexecute whenever anything changed
or more often, because you have events
and you wanna trigger certain methods when an event occurs,
that does not change.
You still bind your events to methods.
You don't bind events to computer properties.
You really only use computer properties
for outputting something like here, the full name.