Now we learned about computed properties,
a key feature for outputting dynamic values
that depend on multiple input values,
or like in this case here on one input value
and one hard-coded value.
They're all this and never reactivity feature
built into Vue, and that would be watchers.
What are Watchers?
Well, a watcher is basically a function
you can tell Vue to execute,
when one of its dependencies changed.
Okay, that sounds just like computed properties,
doesn't it?
Well, indeed you can use Watchers
instead of computed properties
and here's how that would work,
and why you maybe don't wanna do it.
Let me add a full name, data property here like this,
and therefore let's comment out this full name,
computed property so that we don't have a name clash.
You don't wanna use a computed and a data property
with the same name.
Now we can add a new configuration here,
a new option to this object we passed to create app,
again anywhere in their, position doesn't matter.
I'll add it here,
And that's the watch option just like data computed
and methods, this name is not up to you
it's one of the supported features Vue has,
and therefore this has to be watch.
Watch wants an object, just like computed and methods.
And, and here again,
you'll define a bunch of methods.
To be precise here, you can now use a name
you used in a data or computed property
as a name for a watcher method.
For example,
here we could use name,
because we have that name data property
and define it as a method here in watch.
Technically, this is okay,
we'll not have any name clashes here.
This tells Vue one important thing.
Whenever name changes, this watcher method will re execute
and that's really important.
This name here being used here sets up this connection.
That's how watchers work.
You repeat another data or computed property name
in a watcher method as a method name there,
and when you do that,
that watcher method will be executed automatically by Vue,
whenever a property of that name,
so this case, whenever the name property changes.
We could also watch the counter property instead,
but here I wanna watch the name.
And then in here we can specify any logic we want.
We don't return anything because we're not going to use
the watcher anywhere in our HTML code to use a return value.
Instead in here we run logic that should be executed
When the name changed.
For example,
we could update full name here, and set it,
= to this.name + an empty space + Schwartzmuller.
Actually, we don't even need to refer to this.name here,
a watcher function automatically gets the last value,
the latest value of the watch property as an argument.
This is passed in automatically by Vue,
this latest value of the watch property.
Hence, we can accept it as an argument,
name it however you want, and then use it in here.
We actually also could accept a second argument here,
besides the value and that would then be the previous value,
the old value of the watch property.
Here I'm just accepting one
because we only need that one,
but you could accept two arguments If you wanted to.
New value and old value.
And with that we would also update the full name
whenever the name changes.
If we save that and reload, indeed, if I type here,
you have the same behavior as before with one difference
we always see Schwartz Muller here,
but we could also change this, check if value is empty...
It's an empty string and if that's the case,
we set full name equal to an empty string as well.
That would be how we could ensure that full name is empty.
If value is empty, actually of course,
I should then put the other code into an else block Vue,
and now we have that described behavior.
So that's a watcher.
And as you see,
you could use it as an alternative to a computed property.
Now we have a couple of problems
if we use it for that though,
for one,
I would argue that the concept of a computed property
is maybe a bit easier to understand,
but the bigger problem arises If we have a computer property
that would use more than one dependency,
let's say we have a second input.
I just duplicated my input here,
and there we have a last name.
Now we add a new data property,
last name, which initially is an empty string,
and this is bound with the model on that second input.
Now we have these two names.
Now we wanna update the full name whenever the name,
or the last name changed.
To achieve this with a watcher,
we need to add a second watcher because the first one
simply watches the name.
Now we need to add a second one
where we also watch last name and get the value of that.
And in here we have almost the same code,
but we wanna set the full name here,
= to this.name + blank + lost + value
because here we get the latest value of last name
and up there in our first watcher,
we wanna change this to value + blank + this.last name
because we're watching name here.
Now we have two watchers to reflect the full name,
which is managed with two inputs.
And yes, this works, but it's a lot of code,
especially if we compare it to the computed property
alternative.
Let me comment out the full name, data property,
and let's also comment out the watchers.
We could remove them,
but I'll keep them around for reference.
And let's bring back the computed property,
to see how much easier it is with a computed property.
There if we want to use two dependencies,
we simply reference two dependencies like this,
pointing at this last name.
And now we got the desired behavior with less code.
Maybe we should also tweak df check here,
and check if the name is empty or this last name is empty.
If either of the two is empty,
we return an empty full name.
But with that, we got the desired behavior,
and it's really not a lot of code.
It's just this code to get a full name,
dynamically compared that to our two watchers.
Why do we have watchers then if we can use them,
but they're worse?
Because this works but it's not the main scenario
for using watchers.
Watchers are powerful,
if you have a different kind of intent in mind.
Let's come back to our counter here.
Let's say when the counter exceeds 50, anything like that,
we wanna reset it.
That's the type of task where a watcher shines.
We wanna change counter when something happens
so we can watch counter and get its latest value,
to then check if value,
so the value of the counter is greater than 50,
and if that's the case, we set this.counter = 0.
That's the kind of thing where watchers can be helpful.
If you wanna run logic,
that may be all the updates a data property,
but which shouldn't always do that.
For example, here, I only want to set the counter to zero,
if we exceed 50.
A computed property would probably not be the best
alternative here for this kind of task.
You can try solving this with a computed property
and you'll quickly see that you'll face some problems here.
With a watcher, this is easy though.
If we save that and now reload, we can change the counter,
but you'll see if I press add 10 again
and hence who would exceed 50 it's back to zero
and starts again.
That's the kind of task where a watcher can shine.
Another example, would be HTTP requests,
which you wanna send if certain data changes,
or timers which you wanna set, if certain values change.
For example, here, we could say if value exceeds 50,
I want to set a timer to two seconds,
and in the function that executes after the two seconds,
I want to reset the counter.
Like this, that won't work though, because this in here,
won't refer to the same thing,
this would refer to outside of this function
and therefore we can work around that by storing,
this in a number of constant and using that here,
that's nothing Vue specific,
that's just how JavaScript works,
that this key word can be tricky there,
but with that code if I reload,
if I ramp up the timer, it goes above 50,
but it's reset eventually.
Because we set a time out every time the counter changes
and is greater than 50.
That's by the way, all the why it resets multiple times
here, because if I exceed 50 and I keep on going,
I trigger more and more watcher executions
and more and more timers get set.
That's the kind of task where a watcher can be useful
if you wanna run some code, which may be,
but not necessarily also updates some data property
in reaction to a property changing.
If you wanna do that execute code,
because something changed, then watchers can be helpful.
If you just want to calculate some output value dynamically,
computed properties are your friend.