I know that there's,
Methods vs Computed vs Watchers thing.
Can be very confusing.
So it's time for a short summary.
Methods can be used in your template to bind data,
to use them in a interpolation, for example.
To derive data that should be used in the template
or for event binding.
You can use methods for both.
And if you use them in the data binding use case,
so if you use them between curly braces, for example,
to outsource logic from the template to your view instance,
then the method is executed
for every re-render cycle of the component.
So whenever something changes
and the template is re-evaluated,
every method that's called in the template
will be called again.
That's what I showed you a couple of lectures ago.
And therefore,
you should use methods primarily for event binding.
There it's a no brainer.
You always use them
or for data binding,
so with double curly braces, for example,
if you really want them to re-execute
whenever something changes on the page.
Otherwise, you use computed properties
because those can only be used with data binding.
You don't use them with event binding.
And computed properties are great to derive data
that's based on other data with the advantage
that they will only be re-evaluated and re-executed by view
if the dependent data changed.
So if the data used inside of the computed property changed,
they will not be re-evaluated if some other data changed.
And therefore, use them for data that depends on other data.
Last but not least,
Watchers are not directly used in the template.
You don't reference them there,
but you can watch any property,
even computed properties with them.
And that allows you to run code
in reaction to some change data.
For example, to send the HTTP request,
set a timer, stores something in local storage,
whatever it is.
So typically, you should use Watchers
for any non data updates you wanna make.
Whatever you got some behind the scenes work to do
based on some changing data,
you might wanna consider a Watcher.
Amongst the free Watchers
are probably the feature you'll use the least
because you need methods all the time with event binding
and computed properties for outputting data
that depends on other data.