So now, it's almost time to practice again,
but here's what important shorthand,
one way of writing a bit shorter code
which you should be aware of.
Not directly related to computed properties and watchers,
but to view in general.
We used v-on quite a bit
and before we also used v-bind, if you remember.
Now, v-on and v-bind are so common
that there are shorthands for them.
Instead of using v-on:click, v-on:click,
v-on:input and whatever you want to do.
You can replace v-on colon, with an at symbol.
And that's exactly the same thing.
It's just a shorthand provided by view
to make adding event listeners a bit easier.
You can still combine this with modifiers
and still do everything you did before,
you just replace v-on colon with @,
so that you have less code to write.
It's up to you if you want to use that,
you just should be consistent.
So if you do use it, use it for all events, not just some.
And I'm going to use it throughout the course, by the way.
But you don't have to, it's just an alternative.
We also have a shortcut for v-bind.
If we had v-bind:value here,
then we can actually also just omit v-bind
and just have colon value
for binding an attribute dynamically.
So just colon, attribute name
is a shorthand for v-bind colon attribute name
and @event name is a shortcut for a v-on colon event name.
Again, it's up to you, what you prefer,
but you should be consistent
and I'm going to use these shorthands throughout the course.
There is no v-model shorthand, by the way.