At this point,
we learned about data binding with interpolation
and v-bind, about event binding
and Vue's reactivity, especially also with features
like compute properties or Watchers.
And these are all core features,
which you gotta know.
I guess that's why they are in this basics section.
There's one more basic building block
into which I wanna dive together with you.
And that is styling to be precise, dynamic styling.
And I prepared a basic example for that,
which you'll of course find attached to this lecture.
With dynamic styling, I mean that in Vue,
we can change the style of things on the page.
Well, dynamically in reaction to something, for example,
in reaction to a click or to the user entering something.
Let me show you an example here.
Let's first of all, create a new app with Vue.createApp,
passing our object, store it in a constant maybe,
and then call mount on our app to mount it
to a place in our HTML code.
In this case to this section,
which has two styling ID with hash styling.
And now let's say we want to be able to click on those divs
and highlight the div which is active.
Now one way of doing that,
probably not the shortest way,
but definitely a way that should be easy to understand
is that we have a data, property here
or our data object here in this Vue App.
As we did many times before
and in here we keep track of which div,
which demo div is selected.
We could do this with box A selected,
which we set to false initially box B selected
and then box C selected.
So I'm having free data properties
with different names,
which I will basically mentally connect
to those divs.
And initially they're all set to false
because initially let's say no div is selected.
Now let's add a click listener.
We can not just add click listeners, to buttons.
We can listen to clicks on basically any HTML element
and I'll add a method in my methods object therefore,
which I wanted to fire when this div is clicked.
I'll name it boxSelected.
And actually I want to get the box
so an identifier for which box was selected as an input.
And then here I'll check if box is equal
to let's say A, and if that's the case,
I'll set this box A selected to true else if
box is let's say B I'll set
this box B selected to true.
And else if box is C,
I'll set this box C selected to true.
So these are the options we have here.
And now on the click listener,
I wanna point at box selected or to be precise
I'll use this alternative syntax of executing it myself
by adding parentheses so that I can pass an A as a string,
as a value for this first div.
And then repeat this on the other divs
so that we have an easy way
of using one at the same method for setting different boxes
to select it.
Currently, by the way, there is no way of unselectig them
but for the moment, that's all I need.
So now we have ways
of changing these data properties through clicks,
but I mentioned that I wanna dive into styling with you.
Well, let's say wanna highlight when a box is selected,
and we can do that with Vue.
Let's say we wanna change the border color of a box,
if it is selected,
solve this first box, for example,
well, we can set styles either through CSS and CSS classes,
or also with inline styles by using the style attribute,
which is a available on basically any HTML element.
In there you can do things like this, border color red.
If I saved that we have a red color here on the first box,
but of course this now always applies
not just sometimes.
Well, we just need to bind style to a dynamic value
and we can do this with, v-bind
or the shorthand, just colon style.
But now here's a special thing, style and also classes,
as you will see in a couple of minutes are different.
If you bind those dynamically with v-bind,
you can actually use a special syntax supported by Vue
for these specific attributes.
So for a style and for a class,
you can now feed in an object here,
which style normally does not want, but you can use it,
because that's a special Vue feature for styling class
and in there you can have your CSS property name,
border color, however, either wrap between single quotes,
because we have a JavaScript object here and property names
with dashes are not allowed there.
So we either need quotes or recommended and better use
the camel case version of that where you omit the dash
and the character after the dash
simply is that capital character now.
And then you could set this to red here, for example,
or to make it really dynamic
check if box A is selected.
So if this data property here is true,
and use a ternary expression to check if that is truthy.
So if it's true,
and if that's the case after the question mark,
we set this to red.
Otherwise we set it to this gray color.
So to this hex code.
And that's a default ternary expression in JavaScript,
which we can use here since we're binding this dynamically.
This object syntax is a special feature supported by Vue
for the style attributes specifically.
If I now saved it and reload,
we initially have this gray border color,
but if I click on this box, it gets red.
Now there's no way of turning it back to gray at the moment,
because we have no way of making it unselected,
but that's not a problem here
because I want to focus on the dynamic styling.
And that is how you could set up styles dynamically
with Vue, v-bind and this special style binding Syntax.