Now binding inline styles dynamically
as we're doing it here works,
but inline styles have a couple of disadvantages.
They overrule all other styles,
which sometimes is what you'll need,
but often leads to problems.
Therefore in modern web development and CSS,
we typically don't use inline styles too often.
So, let's actually get rid of that
and let me instead show you something else.
How we can bind CSS classes dynamically,
because that's an alternative approach we could use here.
Let's for a moment, go to styles, CSS,
and let's add a new CSS class here,
a new CSS as class selector, I'll name it active,
but you can use any name you want.
And the only rule or the only property
I'll style in there is border color,
which is set to red.
Well actually to make it even easier to see,
let me also change the background color to salmon
but this is optional.
So, now we have to this active CSS class here
in the CSS file, which we can now close.
And now let's say we wanna add this class dynamically
to this div if boxASelected is true.
So, therefore of course,
we can bind the class attribute dynamically
with V bind or this shorthand with just colon class.
Now class of course needs a string now.
The name of the class that should be added, for example,
demo, which is responsible for this default box style,
that's why I'm passing in a string here.
But we could now make sure
that we pass more than just that string
if indeed box A is selected.
So, if box A is selected here is true.
And for that we could again check boxASelected,
so, check this property in a ternary expression.
We can use JavaScript here now
because we're binding this with V bind.
Check if that's true, if it is, we add demo and active.
This needs to be a string
because this is all evaluated as JavaScript here
and we wanna return a string with these classes,
two class if that is selected.
Else, in this ternary expression, we'll just add to demo.
So, that active is only added if box A is selected as true.
And if I reload, this works.
However, this is not the nicest code,
it's a bit hard to read
and imagine how difficult this would be to read
if we had more classes that we wanna toggle dynamically.
Thankfully, just as with style,
Vue JS supports a special syntax,
especially for the class attribute as well
if you're binding it with V bind.
You can pass an object here as well,
which normally would not work.
If you don't bind it, that does not make any sense.
But if you do bind it Vue supports this object syntax
and in there you can now add properties
where the property names reflect your CSS classes
and the values of those properties are true or false
or a true, few or false the result,
that indicates whether that class should be added.
So, we could add demo as a key name,
as a property name and set it to true
so that demo is always added and add active
and set the value of active to boxASelected
so that the active class is added to this div
if boxASelected is truthy.
And if we saved it and reload,
we've got the same behavior as before,
but with much more readable code,
especially if we add more and more classes here,
this stays readable and stays maintainable,
which of course is super important.
And now we could do the same on the other divs as well.
But actually before we do that,
I wanna simplify that even more.
Setting demo to true is a bit redundant,
we always add to that class.
So therefore, thankfully we can remove it from here,
remove it from this object
and instead add the class attribute like this
and set it to demo
and have our dynamically bound class attribute in addition.
So, this one here is not dynamically bound,
I'm not having a colon here.
So, that's the regular class attribute
and I'll set it to demo.
And Vue will basically just recognize that
and never change it.
But then I also to bind class dynamically
and what Vue will do is it will evaluate the result
of this dynamic class binding
and merge it with the hard-coded one here.
With that if I reload, we get the same behavior as before,
but with even less code or even easier to manage code,
I should say.
Well then of course, now we can easily bring that over
to the other divs as well, if we want to
and just check for boxBSelected and boxCSelected.
And with that, we can highlight those boxes as well.
We cannot unmark them at the moment,
but still, this is how you can add dynamic classes
and dynamic styling with Vue.
Now, if you wanna make sure that users
can actually toggle this and not just mark it as active,
we can simply go to our code and change this a little bit
and instead of setting this boxASelected
to true all the time, I'll set it to the opposite
of this boxASelected
so that in the end, if box A was selected,
if it was true, it's now false,
thanks to this exclamation mark.
And this false value is the new value for boxASelected,
and I'll do the same for the other boxes.
And with this simple adjustment,
we ensure that this now is a toggleable,
that we can toggle this and not just set it as active,
but also set it as inactive.