Now you can also,
utilize Computed Properties here if you want.
Because I mentioned having Logic in the HTML Code
is suboptimal.
Now, for it as class binding, it actually is okay.
But if you want to move this Logic here,
out of the HTML Code.
Well, you can simply add Computed Properties here
in your Vue Config Object by adding the Computed Key.
And in there any name of your choice, like, "Box A Classes,"
because here I wanna derive the classes
that should be added to box A
and then simply put this Logic.
Ops.
This Logic here,
which I'm binding to my first box in here
and return it here, return as object in box A classes,
and then bind class here to box A classes,
just like that.
If I reload,
it crashes because of course this now shouldn't be this box
I selected here since I'm now inside of my Vue app.
But now if I reload,
this works just before with a Computed Property.
This can especially be helpful
if you have more complex dynamic class code,
if you're not just referring
to a true or false Boolean here,
but if you had a more complex check
or different if statements here
where you want to return different objects.
In such cases as always Computed Properties
can shine a lot,
but you can also use it here
to simplify your HTML Code a bit more
and move that Logic into JavaScript.
It's optional here, though.
You can do it, but for a styling
for dynamic styling,
it's definitely not a must do,
unless you have very complex code
for finding out whether a class should be added or not.