There's one more syntax supported by Vue
which I don't want to hide from you.
You can have multiple class attributes like this,
but if you have multiple class assignments,
you can also just work with one dynamic class assignment
where you, for example, have this object syntax,
but not passing the object like this,
but instead pass an array where your object,
where you configure which class should be added,
could be one element in the array.
And other elements could be, for example, demo as a string.
So with that, you can also add
multiple potentially dynamically derived classes
to one at the same div by using this array syntax,
which also works just fine.
That's just a number of syntax to be aware of.
You have multiple options here,
and it of course depends on your personal preferences
and also on what you're building,
which option you want to go with,
but that is dynamic styling
and what you can do regarding that in Vue.
Obviously super powerful and super important
as you will all see throughout this course
and the different projects we're going to build
because with dynamic styling,
you can really build amazing user interfaces.