To output data
in your Vue controlled HTML part,
there is a special syntax,
which is only available in HTML parts
that are controlled by Vue,
because what Vue will do behind the scenes
is it will scan this HTML code
you could say,
and detect certain features,
a certain syntax, which it supports.
And the syntax we're going to use here
for outputting text, for outputting content
in your template,
is this one.
Double curly braces, opening and closing.
By default, if you use that in HTML,
this will do nothing.
Well, actually you will simply see
that on the screen thereafter.
If you use the syntax in a Vue controlled HTML snippet,
it will do something special,
between those opening and closing double curly braces.
You can reference your returned data object properties,
like course Goal.
So, here we can write course Goal,
and Vue will make that connection,
will understand, that you wanna output
the content stored in course Goal here.
And it'll do just that.
So, if you save this HTML and JavaScript,
if both is saved and you reload your webpage,
you will see, finish the course and learn Vue here,
just like that.
And this is pretty amazing, even though of course,
it's a very simple app,
but keep in mind that this text is stored in JavaScript.
Yet, it's rendered on the screen,
thanks to Vue and this special syntax.
And this syntax here is called interpolation.
You don't need to remember this, but that's its name.
Interpolation, simply means that in here,
you can reference properties, that are part of that object,
you return in data,
and then the value of the property will be output
instead of this part.
And Vue automatically detect this
and do all that outputting part for you.
If you use this syntax.
And just to make this really clear,
if you would use this anywhere else,
let's say here in the header,
which is not Vue controlled,
you would just see this as text
and it would not be replaced
because that is really only a Vue feature.
This interpolation syntax.
And this interpolation syntax is key.
We're going to use it a lot, through out the course
because it's one of the key features of Vue,
which is why I'm getting started with it.
It's also worth noting,
that you cannot just output text like this,
but you could also output a number,
if I save that.
And you could also output something like true or false,
if you want it to.
Now if you have an array in there,
let's say, you can always output that as we see.
So, it's really flexible.
You can, for example,
also, I'll put an object like this.
So, it's really flexible regarding what you can do,
but here we want that string.
So I'm going to use that.
Now that's interpolation and the data property,
in the object you use for configuring your app,
your Vue app.
And this is the first very important takeaway
or the first two important takeaways.
These are two core features,
data and interpolation,
which we're going to use throughout the entire course
and which you will definitely use
in any Vue app you're building.