Now we covered two super important features.
How we create a Vue instance and configure the data,
that we can use there,
and how we can output data with interpolation.
Now, you don't always want to use interpolation
for outputting data, though.
Here's an example.
Let's say we have a second paragraph, where I say,
"learn more about Vue",
and I want to make sure that "about Vue" is a link.
Of course we can use a anchor tag with the ref attribute
for that, and wrap that around "about Vue".
If I do that, this is what we get.
And now in here, we can pass in our link.
Now, just as before, we could absolutely hard code
this here in our HTML code,
but let's again store the link value in our Vue app instead,
and then add some syntax to output the stored value here,
simply so that later in the next step, we can make this
a bit more dynamic.
So for that, I'm going to add a second property
to this object which is returned in data,
and I'll name it "vueLink".
And now this again is a string that can lead to a page
where you can learn more about Vue.
Now here, I'm simply going to use the official Vue webpage,
but again you can of course use anything here.
Now, this vueLink property now holds the link
that should be output here, and we can of course try
to use our curly braces here, just as we did it
between the paragraph tags, now I'm doing this
on the ref attribute.
So here we then point at vueLink,
save this, reload, and click "about Vue"
as you see, this fails, and, why does it fail,
well, let's inspect this
with the browser developer tools real quick,
I'm using Chrome here, where you can right click something
to inspect it, and you will see that
the value for the ref attribute
is actually the unconverted double curly brace syntax.
So clearly Vue did not replace this
with the actual value stored in vueLink,
as it did it before for this course goal part.
Now why did Vue not do that?
We are inside of the Vue controlled HTML code.
So Vue should detect this.
Well, the reason is simple.
This double curly brace syntax is only available
between opening and closing HTML tags, you could say.
So anywhere, where you would, well, output actual content.
If you wanna pass in a dynamic value to an attribute,
like here, where I wanna set the value of the ref attribute,
dynamically with help of Vue, we need to use
a different syntax, which thankfully is available though.
And that's the Vue binding syntax.
For that, we use a so called vue directive,
which is simply an extra instruction
we add in the HTML code.
And we can use such directives on HTML elements,
like on this anchor element.
The directive we need here is v-bind.
V-bind is a reserved name, detected and understood by Vue,
and you can tell that it's by Vue
because it starts with "v-".
All built in directives which ship with Vue,
start with "v-", and we're going to see
a couple of other ones too throughout the course.
Now, what does this v-bind directive do?
As I said, a directive is basically an instruction.
An instruction we give to Vue to do something.
And v-bind tells Vue to bind, so to set,
the value of something,
and the "of something" part basically just means
of an attribute on an HTML element.
And to let Vue know which attribute's value to set,
we add a colon after v-bind,
and then the attribute name, in this case ref,
and this is the full syntax which vue will understand,
to dynamically set a value of an HTML element attribute,
in this case of the ref attribute.
This tells Vue, please find, please set
the value of the ref attribute to something,
and now the "to something" is passed between
the opening and closing double quotes here,
and here again, you can now reference a value of
your data object, so in this case, vueLink for example,
just like this.
So this here, v-bind, is basically, you could say,
the attribute alternative to this interpolation syntax.
You use interpolation between HTML tags,
and if you need to set the value on an HTML tag,
so, to an attribute like this,
you use v-bind.
If you now save this and reload,
we now click this link, I'm taken to the Vue docks.
So I'm basically forwarded to the page this link points at.
So now this works, and v-bind, just like interpolation,
is a key feature you need to know,
because typically, you don't just want to output content
between opening and closing tags,
often you have the scenario that you need to bind,
that you need to set the value of some HTML attribute
to some Vue managed data, and with v-bind,
that's very easy to do.