So with interpolation and V-bind,
we learned about two key features for outputting,
and for a using Vue-managed data in the HTML code.
And that is really important.
Now let's make our app at least a bit more dynamic.
And for data, let's say we actually
have two possible courseGoals,
which we wanna output here.
And for the moment, we'll randomly decide
which one to output.
Now for that, we need to run some code.
We need to basically roll a dice you could say,
and then either use this text
or another text as a courseGoal.
And we can do this with another option.
We can set on this Vue app object.
We already set the data option.
Now it's time to learn about a new option.
And that's the methods option.
Methods allows you to define functions
which should execute when something happens
when you call them for example, or as you will learn later,
when a user event like a button click occurs.
Two methods you pass a JavaScript object.
So that's important difference to data.
Data itself was a function a method,
methods takes an object, which will be full of methods,
so of functions, but these functions
are now totally up to you.
You can name them however you want.
For example, outputGoal, but this is totally up to you.
This can be any name you want.
methods on the other hand,
just like data is a reserved term, is a reserved name.
But inside of this methods object,
you can use whatever you want.
The only important thing here is,
that all your properties you defined in this methods object
needs to be functions
because they need to be callable as functions.
And you can either do it like this
or use the method shorthand in here.
Just as we did with data.
Now, in outputGoal, we could now calculate
a randomNumber with math random,
which is a built in function in JavaScript.
totally unrelated to Vue, it's a core JavaScript function.
And it will simply calculate a randomNumber
between zero and one.
And here, we could then simply add an if check
and say if randomNumber is smaller than zero dot five.
We wanna return learn Vue, as a goal.
And else, return master Vue whatever you want,
those strings are up to you.
And now we got this function, this method outputGoal,
which will either return this or this text.
Now we wanna use this text here in this paragraph
to well, display a different text every time
this page is reloaded.
So for that, we to call this function somehow,
so that it executes.
And the cool thing is we can call a method,
so a function defined in this methods object
in our HTML code,
just as we can point at a data property, you can do both.
So here right now we're pointing at a data property.
But we can also instead if we want
to execute a function that is defined in methods,
that's just important, it needs to be defined and methods.
So adding outputGoal here,
directly in that config object you pass to create app
would not work, for example.
But since outputGoal is defined in methods,
we can call it here.
And since we wanna call it, we need to add parentheses here,
just like in regular JavaScript.
And that's the interesting part, by the way,
in your Vue controlled HTML code
in this interpolation syntax,
but also when using display binding syntax,
you can execute simple JavaScript code.
For example, here, we could also execute
one plus one if we wanted to.
We could also execute math random here, if you want a to.
What you can't do in here is write complex code.
For example, you can't use if statements in here,
this will not work.
But you can use ternary expressions,
and you can write any JavaScript expression
between your double curly braces and when using v-bind.
And therefore since we can use
such basic JavaScript expressions,
we can also call outputGoal here like this.
And if I save that and reload,
I see learn Vue.
If I reload, at some point, I'll see master Vue
I'll see a different value from time to time
because we always calculate a brand new value
because this gets called.
And I'm showing this to you because it is important
to understand how Vue works
that you can execute JavaScript expressions here
between the curly braces and when using v-bind.
And that this gives you a lot of flexibility.
Because just by using this very simple example,
our application here is at least a bit more dynamic,
because now we don't always see the same text here.
Instead, after some reloads, it changes.
And that is a more dynamic application,
which we can easily build with Vue,
and which we couldn't build
with just HTML without JavaScript.
So with that, we're already getting closer to seeing
why Vue is really amazing,
and we built our first
at least a bit more dynamic application.