So now we know how to build our Vue app,
how to output content or bind attributes.
And then we can either set up some data in data
and refer to that in our HTML code,
or then we can also define methods which are called.
It really depends on what you're building
and what your application goal is in the end.
Now, before we practice those first important concepts,
there are a couple of other things you should know about
Vue and how to work with its data.
For example, let's say we have our courseGoals
stored in data properties.
We've got our coarseGoalA here,
and we got our coarseGoalB here,
Master Vue and build amazing apps.
So, we got our two different goals here now.
And instead of returning hardcoded strings here
in outputGoal, I wanna output one of these two Goals,
which are defined in data.
This is very easy to do in Vue,
but it uses a special feature or a syntax,
which you should be aware of.
Let's say here, if the random number
is smaller than dot five, I wanna return courseGoalA.
Now we can't just write courseGoalA here.
This would not be valid JavaScript.
With this code, JavaScript would look for
a courseGoalA variable or constant, which it wouldn't find
because here courseGoalA is not a variable or constant,
it's a property of this object.
But instead we can use a syntax,
which you probably wouldn't think that it works.
You can use this.courseGoalA.
Now, depending on your level of JavaScript knowledge,
this might look very strange.
The this keyword is a core keyword in JavaScript,
and it can be tricky, but in this context,
this should not refer to this object here.
It should refer to something else.
And it normally would, but Vue does some magic here.
It basically takes all the data you return
in this data object, which you return the data method,
and it merges it into a global Vue instance object.
So into your Vue app object, you could say.
So, these three data properties are available
in a behind the scenes managed Vue app object.
Your methods are also available there.
And they do have access to anything stored
in that global object through the this keyword.
And that's why in this custom method inside of methods,
we can use this to refer for example, to our data.
So, we can do this here as well, this.courseGoalB.
And if I saved it and reload,
we therefore now output these different course goals,
which are stored in our data with help of this method.
And having that knowledge of the this keyword
and what it refers to inside of your methods
in your Vue app, that's important,
because we're going to work with that a lot
throughout this course.