So at this point,
the good news is that we covered almost all important
features and functionalities that are related to
outputting data,
namely interpolation and the v-bind directive.
Also combined with the knowledge that you can output either
data or the result of method calls like we're doing it here.
Now there is one more feature,
one more directive you should be aware of.
Let's say one of the two goals,
let's say course goal B
is actually not just a simple string like this,
but this is some HTML code.
And this could be a scenario
you have in application.
Where you, for example,
fetched a data and it should be output from a database
and from there you're getting some structured HTML code.
Now if you use HTML elements in this string,
and you output this with interpolation.
So with the double curly braces,
you'll see that the HTML elements are just output as text.
So they are not interpreted as HTML.
And that actually is a useful security feature because it
protects you against cross site scripting attacks.
So this is good.
But sometimes you want to output this as HTML
and not as text that looks like HTML.
And for that you've got another directive you can use.
And that is the v-html directive.
We saw v-bind before.
V-bind can be used to bind,
so to set the values of attributes.
With v-html,
you set the content between opening and closing text
of an element,
but you now tell Vue
that the content should be interpreted as HTML.
So it should not be output as text
as it is with double curly braces.
And therefore you no longer use double curly braces here,
but instead, the value you pass to v-html
between the double quotes here
would be coarse goal B for example,
or also if you want it to,
the result of calling output goal.
This also works.
And if I now reload,
you see from time to time,
there's this dh2 tag.
The text is just green,
which is why you don't see it because of my styling,
but this now is interpreted as HTML.
And of course goal A is also interpreted as HTML,
but in there I got no HTML text.
So this is a feature you can use.
I'm going to comment it out here,
because we don't need it here,
but I wanted to make you aware of it.
If you get some contents stored in your Vue app,
which contains HTML code, that should be treated as HTML.
The v-html directive, which is built into Vue
will help you with that.
Now chances are, you'll not need it too often,
and you should definitely not use it as a default.
Because you can introduce security issues with that
because you basically circumvent the built in
cross site scripting attack protection
you have with the double curly braces.
But if you know what you're doing,
and you need to output something as HTML,
the v-html directive is your friend.
Well,
and these are some basics about working with the Vue app
and outputting content with data,
or with a method which you call.
And therefore I'd say,
next it's time to practice the subject.