Now, since it is a huge course,
I want to ensure that you get the most out of this course.
And for that, I've got a couple of tips and tricks.
Obviously I recommend that you watch the videos.
It's a video-on-demand course, after all.
Watch them at your pace,
and use the video player controls to speed me up,
if I'm going too slow or slow me down,
if I'm going too fast.
In addition, I always recommend that you code along.
Try things on your own,
and maybe pause the video and try writing the code,
for what we're about to add on your own.
And even if you don't do that,
pause the video from time to time,
to catch up with me to code along,
or as I just said, also code ahead.
You might also need to repeat certain concepts
from time to time.
This is totally normal.
It's a lot of content in this course,
and therefore definitely feel free,
to repeat videos or entire sections,
if something is unclear,
or you forgot about a certain concept.
With the big course projects we have,
throughout this course, though,
you will also often get a chance of seeing
all the concepts you learn,
coming together in one project though.
So that will also help with understanding these concepts,
and seeing how they work together.
Now, of course, sometimes you might also get stuck.
You might face an error,
or something might be unclear.
Two sources I recommend that you consider in such cases,
would be Google and stack overflow.
You will find stack overflow automatically if you Google.
And I'm serious about this,
if you face some error message,
if something is unclear,
put it into Google and search the web,
often you'll find a couple of threads,
on that problem specifically.
And very often that will help you solve your problem.
But of course, if you don't find a solution there,
or if you are stuck, if something is unclear,
we also got a Q and A section,
in which you can ask and answer.
And I'm really serious about the answering part.
Asking is simple. Answering is hard,
but ultimately you will learn a lot more,
if you help your fellow students,
and you also answer in the Q and A section.
Of course, I'm also there to help you,
and I'll do my very best to provide quick answers,
on course related questions.
But definitely use this as a forum for discussion.
In addition, if you are facing errors,
if you got an error in your code,
which I don't get in the videos,
if you're facing an error,
compare your code to mine.
You'll find snapshots, code snapshots attached by me,
on the last lecture of every course module,
of every course section.
On the last lecture of every section,
you'll find code snapshots for the different lectures,
in that section.
And the attachment name,
will tell you to which lecture it belongs.
And you can use these snapshots to compare my code to yours.
You can also replace your code with mine temporarily,
step by step, to narrow down the issue,
and find out where your code differs,
and what might be causing an error.
And with that, you got all the tools you need,
to get a lot out of this course.
So let's jump right into the next section,
where we will start with the basics of Vue.