So what is Vue.js
or just vue as it's also called.
Vue.js is a JavaScript framework
that makes building interactive
and reactive web frontends,
which are basically web applications
that run in the browser,
so in the end what the user sees, easier.
This is a nice sentence
and it would be a correct definition,
but it might not be too helpful,
so let me make this a bit clearer
and let's highlight the important parts here.
And of course, one important part is JavaScript,
Vue.js is for JavaScript and it uses JavaScript,
it's all about JavaScript
because JavaScript is the programming language
which we can use in the browser.
We can run it in the browser
after a page was loaded by the user.
It allows us to manipulate what the user sees on the screen
without fetching a new page from the server
and that allows us to provide rich user experiences
and I'll come back to this
rich user experiences point in just a second.
But it's not just for JavaScript,
indeed Vue.js is a JavaScript framework,
now what does framework mean?
A framework, not just in JavaScript,
but in any programming language
is basically a third party library
which means it's code not written by you,
but by someone else
which exposes certain utility functionalities,
certain methods, certain tools,
which you don't have to write on your own
and that's important, unlike a regular library,
a framework is a library
that does not just give you those extra functionalities,
but which also gives you a set of rules you could say.
It gives you a clear guidance,
a clear approach that you should follow
when it comes to building your application,
it basically gives you a clear idea
and structure of how to write your application code,
so it's the utility functions plus the rules.
Now, why would we use Vue.js?
We also have that in a sentence
because with it we can build interactive
and reactive web frontends.
Reactive is a pretty fancy term,
but in the end what it means is that
our app should be very responsive to what the user does.
If a user enters something on the screen,
we want to be able to react to that,
for example, to show validation errors below a input field,
we want to be able to show overlays with warning messages,
we wanna give a user a very modern look
and feel in our web application.
Often we try to achieve what we know from mobile apps
and I'll come back to that as well.
So we wanna provide a great user experience in the end
and Vue.js makes it easier for us to achieve that
and the web frontends part is all the important.
This basically means that Vue.js is involved with
what the user sees,
it's not a server side framework,
we don't use it with PHP or with node,
well, we can use it with all of that,
but simply in a combination,
but it doesn't help us write better PHP or node.js code
because vue.js is for the browser side JavaScript.
With HTML, CSS and JavaScript
and possibly Vue.js in the browser,
we can control what the user sees
and we can provide rich user interface in the web.
And Vue.js is a framework
that helps us with building such a JavaScript
driven user interface running in the browser
for our web application that might be talking to a server,
but it's all about the browser side code
that helps us achieve that.
Now why would we use something like Vue.js?
Why would we want this reactive web frontend?
Well, let's take a step back
and let's not think about web applications,
let's think about mobile applications.
Mobile applications are very responsive,
things happen instantly,
we basically have like one screen
where we add overlays,
where we render lists,
we can navigate to different screens
with a smooth animation,
it all feels like one unit you could say.
So mobile apps and also desktop apps feel very reactive,
we don't have to wait for new pages to load,
we don't have to wait for HTML to be downloaded
and rendered by the browser,
instead, the entire user interface is already there,
the entire user interface is part of the mobile app
the user installed
and the only thing that might be loaded behind the scenes
is data.
Now in web apps, traditionally,
we click a link and we wait for a new page to load
and that happens over and over again.
We might enter some data in a form,
we click a button,
that data is submitted and as a response,
we get a new HTML page.
So in a traditional web page,
we wait for responses all the time.
JavaScript can help us here,
JavaScript can speed this up
and JavaScript in the browser
allows us to provide a more modern web application,
a more modern user interface.
JavaScript has the huge advantage of running in the browser
on the loaded page,
that means we have a language running in the browser,
which can be used to change that page
without fetching new HTML behind the scenes.
Instead, we can manipulate the HTML structure,
the so-called DOM, Document Object Model
of a page with JavaScript.
And that means that in modern
JavaScript driven web applications,
we're not sending a request to get a new HTML page,
instead, we only do this once
and thereafter, we just exchange data behind the scenes
and we use client side JavaScript
and possibly frameworks like Vue
to update what's on the screen.
And we're using solutions like Vue.js
because just JavaScript may not be ideal.
Theoretically, we can build any kind of web application
with just vanilla JavaScript,
so with just JavaScript without any extra frameworks
or libraries.
No framework like Vue is needed in reality,
but it wouldn't be much fun to use just JavaScript
because we have to write all the code,
all the logic on our own,
we have to reinvent the wheel over and over again.
We might even write sub optimal code
and introduce errors and bugs
because we have to write everything from scratch
and we have to do these things correctly,
otherwise we might have poor performance or security issues.
Working in a team might also be harder
because not everyone knows our code structure,
the philosophy behind our code
and how to use our code.
And that's why we use something like Vue,
it gives us a clear rule set
in which we have to work,
which everyone in a team has to use
and we don't have to figure out
all the small nitty gritty details
like updating a part on the page,
instead, we can focus on our core business logic with Vue
and let Vue do the heavy lifting of updating the page
and of doing all the annoying stuff
which we would have to do otherwise.
That's why we use frameworks like Vue
and for the course, this will become obvious
once we dive into all the features Vue offers
and how easy those features make it
to build amazing web applications and user interfaces.