So, in order to get our hands dirty,
I prepared a very simple dummy project for you,
You'll find it attached to this lecture
as a zip file which you can download and extract,
and in that extracted folder,
you will find three files, an app.js file,
an index.html file and a styles.css file.
Now, here, I opened this extracted folder
with Visual Studio Code, the code editor I'm
going to use throughout this course.
Now, you can use any code editor or IDE of your choice.
You don't need a specific tool,
but, I strongly recommend Visual Studio Code,
which you can get for free from code.visualstudio.com.
It's available for macOS, Windows and Linux,
so you can use it on any platform,
and you can simply download and install it from that page.
And, once you did that, you can open the attached extracted
folder with File, Open and then navigate to that folder
and open it.
You can close the welcome screen you might see
in Visual Studio Code, and if you want to get the exact same
look as I do, under View, Appearance, you can control which
sidebars are visible or not visible, and I only have the
sidebar and the editor area open.
I, for example, don't have the activity bar,
which you might still have.
I am also zoomed in here, and under Code, Preferences,
Color theme, I am using the Dark+ theme.
Now, you can configure this however you want,
but that is the style I am using.
Now, with that, let's start writing some code
and I will actually start
by writing some non-view code first,
so that we thereafter can see
why using a framework like Vue.js might be a good idea.
On this demo project which I prepared,
we can add Goals,
we've got a test goal at the moment,
and we will delete that soon,
but, now, whenever I add a new goal here,
like 'Finish the course'
I want to make sure when at 'Add Goal' is clicked,
this goal appears in that list down there.
In the index.html file, we've got some
mark up for that input field label button,
and then that list with the dummy list item,
which we can delete now.
And, I'm importing some styles which I prepared for you,
we don't have to care about those,
it's not a CSS course after all,
but we do all the import app.js,
and here we can write some some JavaScript code
to fetch the user input when the button is clicked,
create a new list item,
and add that to that list of list items here.
And, that's what I want to do first now,
with just JavaScript, so without Vue.
In app.js for that,
we first of all need to get access to the input,
so that we can read the entered value,
we need to get access to the button,
so that we can listen to click events on the button,
and we need to get access to the unordered list here,
so that we can add new list items.
Therefore, I will create three constants here
in app.js.
The first one is the buttonEl constant, lets say,
this name, of course, is up to you,
where I use document.querySelector
to select the only button we have on this page.
So, now, pointer to that dom element, to that JavaScript
object representation of that button element,
Is stored in that buttonEl const.
I'll do the same for the input element,
with document.querySelector ('input')
and also for the listEl with document.querySelector ('ul')
for unread list.
Now, we can add a click Lister with JavaScript
to this button by reaching out to the
buttonEl and calling addEventListener,
where we then listen to the click event like this
by passing click as a string,
as a first argument.
The second argument now needs to be the
function that should be executed when the click occurs,
For that, we can define a new function here,
addGoal could be the name,
which should be triggered upon a click,
so here we can then point at addGoal.
We don't execute it here, we just point at it
by repeating its name, so that the function
is executed for us when a click occurs,
Now, in this function we want to get
whatever the user entered.
So, we can get the entered value by
reaching out to inputEl.value, being an input element,
at which were pointing here, it will have a value property
that's vanilla JavaScript, that's built into JavaScript
that we have this value property on input elements,
where we then can extract the value the user entered
into this input.
And now, we can create a new list item element by calling
document.createElement which is a built-in method provided
by the browser, to create new dom elements programmatically
with JavaScript.
Here, we can provide 'li' to create a list item
element, and then we can use that newly created list item
element to set its text content, so the text between the
opening and closing text, of that list item, equal to the
entered value.
And then, we can reach out to the listEl, so to
our overall list, and call append or appendChild,
both will work here, I'll go for appendChild,
and append our list itemEl,
which we just created.
If we do all of that, and we reload I can add
'Finish the course!' and add this goal.
And thereafter, for example, also add 'Learn Vue!'
as a goal.
Now, let's say we also want to reset the input
once a goal was added, we could do that by, again,
using our inputEl and setting
value equal to an empty string.
This will set the value in the input element to an
empty text, and therefore clears it.
So, with that if we reload again,
and I 'Finish the course!', now this would be
cleared.
Now, that's just JavaScript, no Vue in action,
and it's obviously a very very very trivial demo website.
Still, we will now use Vue and you'll thereafter
see why Vue might be quite interesting, as it makes building
websites more fun.
I'll then also talk about the
differences between Vue and this approach,
but first of all, let's switch to Vue in the next lecture.