Now there is certainly a lot of magic
in there at the moment.
But the key thing is that with Vue,
we just find the end result,
and we use these special features in the HTML code
to connect HTML to data and logic managed in the Vue app.
And we will learn about a lot
of features Vue has to offer to us
which allows to build any kind of app.
And being able to do this
and follow this declarative approach
where we declared the result instead
of the steps of getting there,
that allows us to build super large applications
without any issues.
Whereas just JavaScript,
if we would have a more complex app,
would quickly run into problems.
We would quickly face issues there in bigger apps
if we would use just JavaScript,
and writing an application that's error free
and offers great performance would be difficult
with just JavaScript.
With Vue, it'll be easy.
And in this course, you're going to learn all about Vue.