So now that we had a first look at Vue,
let me quickly walk through what you'll find in this course,
to give you an overview of all the content in this course
and then we'll dive deeper into Vue.
Now in this lecture,
I want to talk about the development setup I'll be using.
I already mentioned that I work with Visual Studio Code,
which is this editor,
which I would recommend that you also use.
And in there,
I showed you that I used the dark plus color theme.
Now I'm not using any other special settings here,
which you should know,
but I will use one shortcut from time to time,
which is really handy.
So under preferences, keyboard shortcuts,
you can search for format document.
And this shortcut,
which you can bind in case you don't have it yet,
will automatically format the code
to make it a bit more readable.
For example, if that would be indented,
it would work technically, but it would be a bit strange.
It would look strange, it would be a bit hard to read.
With that shortcut, it will be reformatted.
And in case that's not working for you,
you can also go to View, Extensions,
to browse the extensions marketplace
and search for Prettier there.
And make sure you install
the Prettier Code Formatting Extension.
If you do that, once you install it,
if you reload, that format shortcut should work for you.
You can ensure that Prettier is getting used for formatting
by going to preferences settings,
and then there search for format.
And under Editor, Default Formatter,
make sure prettier-vscode is selected.
That's one setting I would recommend that you use
to have more readable code.
And that said, this is the setup I will work with,
and this is the editor You will see me using
throughout this course.