So what is in this course then,
what does this course have to offer?
Well, a lot, this is a huge course.
I completely updated it with the release of view free
and I'll keep updating it
and it has tons of content.
We'll take a deep dive into view
and we'll start at the absolute basics.
No prior view knowledge is required for this course,
and we will walk through all these important basics,
step by step.
We will have modules, course sections
where we explore the base syntax, templates,
directives, working with data and methods,
computed properties and Watchers,
and you will learn what all these things are
and how to use them and how they work together
and this will give us the foundation so to say.
Now we'll also thereafter explore intermediate concepts,
we're going to explore components
and component communication.
We'll take a look behind the scenes of view
to see how it works under the hood
and to understand its magic.
We'll learn how to work with forums and user input,
sending http requests,
how to implement routing
and load different pages in a view app
even if it's a single page app,
yes, that sounds strange, but it will work.
We'll dive into animations with you
and we're not even done thereafter,
we'll also explore advanced concepts,
we will dive into working with Vuex for state management.
We'll explore authentication in view apps,
how to deploy and optimize your view app.
We'll have a look at the composition API,
which was introduced with view free
and when I say a look,
I mean a huge module
where we dive super deeply into it.
We will learn how we may reuse code
with and without the composition API
and that's really not even all,
there is so much content in this course.
But we'll not just walk through all these topics and theory,
instead, I prepared dozens of small demos
and mini projects for you,
which we use in the different modules
to learn about different concepts.
And we also got multiple bigger course projects
where we will start from scratch together
and implement all those features
in the context of bigger demos,
in the context of bigger projects
which are then of course, for example,
could also add to your portfolio.
In addition, you'll find assignments
and challenges in this course,
with challenges I mean that I will sometimes tell you
to pause a video and try something on your own and
you can then do that to practice this on your own
and overall you will get all the theory
and all the practice you need with this course,
it's a huge course with tons of content.